ERNEST LOUIS

Americus, GA 31719 | (470) 528-3127 | ernest_louis@outlook.com Portfolio: <u>ernestlouis.github.io/portfolio/</u> | linkedin.com/in/ernestlouis| GitHub: https://github.com/ErnestLouis

SQL DEVELOPER

SQL development professional with solid analytical skills in writing effective relational queries for database solutions. Exemplary ability to work independently using my ETL processing experience, as well as utilizing effective verbal and written communication skills with a team to derive at collaborative solutions. Which has afforded me the opportunity to gain breadth and depth in Data Analytics.

Technical Skills

- · Platforms: Windows 7/10, Mac OS X, Android, Linux (Red Hat, Ubuntu, Linux Mint)
- · Programming Languages: C#, C/C++, SQL, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- · Technology/Frameworks: Git, GitHub, OOP, Excel
- · Management: Agile/Kanban Methodologies
- · BI & Reporting: Tableau, Reporting Services (SSRS), Integration Services (SSIS)
- · Databases/Tools: MS SQL Server, Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB, PL/SQL, T-SQL, Oracle

Experience

COVID 19- SQL DATA EXPLORATION PROJECT

2021-2022

- · Obtained accurate and up-to date COVID 19 data to perform a global exploration in sql server.
- · Wrote complex SQL Queries, Stored Procedure, Triggers, Views & Indexes using both DML and DDL commands.
- · Project Link: https://github.com/ErnestLouis/SQL data-exploration/blob/main/SQLQuery ExplorationProject.sql

COVID 19-DASHBOARD- TABLEAU VISUALIZATION PROJECT

2021-2022

- · Created dashboard design with effective data visualization of large data volumes using various data sources (SQL server, Postgres, and spreadsheets) from Covid-19 exploration results.
- · Implemented different Action filters, Parameters and calculated fields to create intricate dashboards.
- https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/ernest2189/viz/Covid Dashboard 16474568760220/Dashboard1?publish=yes

NASHVILLE_HOUSING-DATA CLEANING SQL PROJECT

2020-2021

- · Obtained raw Airbnb housing data and transformed it in SQL Server allowing for practical analysis.
- · Implemented different Action filters, Parameters and calculated fields to create intricate dashboards.
- · Clean, transform and model data to ensure and improve accuracy of metrics calculations
- · https://github.com/ErnestLouis/sql datacleaning/blob/main/nashville housing.sql

Education

BS-COMPUTER SCIENCE WITH CONCENTRATION IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING | MAY 2020 | SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY

· Cumulative GPA: 3.6

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS:

· Presidents List